<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fateful Triangle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/fateful-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/fateful-triangle/</guid>
      <description>After deep reflection, I still lack the ability to properly give my feedback while remaining professional. This was an incredibly difficult read. Not only was it incredibly lengthy and full of citations and footnotes, it was dense with historical information and new vocabulary. I found myself looking up definitions, synopsis&amp;rsquo; of political parties and events, and having to watch numerous supplemental material to actually follow along. Was this a good thing?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhythm of War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/rhythm-of-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/rhythm-of-war/</guid>
      <description>Previous: Dawnshard&#xA;Wow. Completely floored that I was so captivated by this entry. I began as a book 4 hater; it felt like so much had been accomplished in the first three, what else could possibly happen to our cast of characters? Well, it turns out, a lot can happen and change, which is a recurring theme not only throughout this series, but especially in this one. Almost all of our main characters are going through internal and external factors that push them to make decisions, some life-altering, others not so much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dawnshard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/dawnshard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/dawnshard/</guid>
      <description>Previous: Oathbringer&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who keeps telling Brando Sando to keep making Novellas, but whoever it is needs to actually read them. I really can&amp;rsquo;t justify this being it&amp;rsquo;s own story. Even more than the first, this felt like a different type of filler. Filler with the audacity to be a hardcover.&#xA;My issues don&amp;rsquo;t come with the story at all really. I actually enjoyed Rysn, and thought every time she was on the page she felt real.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1991 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/ring/</guid>
      <description>One that&amp;rsquo;s been on my reading list since I was a kid and saw the dynamic spiral cover, Ring is the original book that inspired the prolific and perfectly-spoofed movie of the same name. Hearing this was a series made me nervous this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great, but I ended up enjoying it at some parts.&#xA;It went by really fast. The main character was the worst dude. Hated how much he clearly did not care about his wife and kids until he put them in danger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/do-androids-dream-of-electric-sheep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1968 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/do-androids-dream-of-electric-sheep/</guid>
      <description>Not remembering much from my initial watch of Blade Runner, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect going into this one. I did really enjoy A Scanner Darkly by Dick, so I expected to like this one despite not knowing much. I was not disappointed, and after blowing through this in 2 days I can say I really enjoyed it.&#xA;The philosophical questions presented combined with the loose answers they provide were interesting and engaging enough for me to think about throughout the read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edgedancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/edgedancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/edgedancer/</guid>
      <description>Previous: Words of Radiance&#xA;Definitely a novella that took me too long to finish, and not really because I was enjoying it. More so because I didn&amp;rsquo;t love Lift as a character. I was actually going to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t hate their childish behavior, but typing that out I had a gut feeling I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself.&#xA;I really didn&amp;rsquo;t like how childish Lift was. Maybe that was her point, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp onto the story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oathbringer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/</guid>
      <description>Holy Moly. What a ride. This book took FOREVER to finish. Exactly 3 months and a day to be exact. But it was so worth it.&#xA;A true continuation from Words of Radiance, this book follows the logical progression from where that book left off and really begins to open up the world. There are still lots of secrets left to unfold (Who is Wit? Who is the Cremling God that Lift meets in Edgedancer?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Road</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/the-road/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 14 2024&#xA;I finished The Road a few days ago and I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected fondly on the experience. Slow burn isn&amp;rsquo;t the word I&amp;rsquo;d use; perhaps a slow agonizing death. Because by the end, I was emotionally exhausted. It asks a lot of you. Sit through the gray, dim world that the story takes place in. Hope to some God the end is worth it. In my opinion, I think it was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words of Radiance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 02 2024&#xA;I finished Words of Radiance two days ago, and it initially got a 4 out of 5. I loved the book. I really did, and was invested from start to finish.&#xA;It took me about 3 weeks (3 weeks and 3 days says Goodreads) and it really flew by. I enjoyed tackling such a huge tome of a novel.&#xA;The characters were awesome, even if I felt like the interlude characters could have been longer to make them a bit more memorable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Are Not Expected To Understand This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/you-are-not-expected-to-understand-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/you-are-not-expected-to-understand-this/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 26 2024&#xA;26 short essays on the pieces/lines of code that shaped the modern understanding of computer science.&#xA;6/3/24&#xA;Halfway through, I think some of the stories are interesting. Some of the articles don&amp;rsquo;t go as deep as I think they could/should; some bring up gender/race for seemingly no reason&amp;hellip;others actually delve deeper into the politics of it encouragingly.&#xA;I started Topics I&amp;rsquo;m Interested In because of this book pretty much.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
