<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Communist Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-communist-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 1848 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-communist-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moby Dick</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 1851 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the reason we write? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s the right way to start this review, but it was something that bothered me the entire time reading Moby Dick. What was the reason for all of this lexical analysis? Was there any benefit to my experience knowing the nitty gritty details of how whales are killed, dissected, and harvested for materials?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At first I thought it was meaningless; fluff to drive out the length of the novel. Fortunately, after finishing it and doing some more research, Herman&amp;rsquo;s expansive diatribes are somewhat useful. At the time of publishing (1851) the knowledge of whales and their general species was largely misinformed. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go research to find that out, Ishmael literally tells you in great detail all of the faults of his modern-day understanding of the great leviathans. Part adventure story of course, but also part learning experience. I started to enjoy the longer chapters a little more when put into that perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Glass Castle</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-glass-castle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-glass-castle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What began as a search for a birthday gift for my mother, became a dive deep into the life of Jeannette Walls. In true Richie fashion, I picked the biggest downer I could&amp;rsquo;ve picked for a happy birthday. Knowing nothing about the book, I had saw it a few times show up as a &amp;ldquo;BookTok&amp;rdquo; recommendation, and even appear on my mom&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Want to Read&amp;rdquo; list on her Goodreads account. Knowing that there was a book in common the both of us wanted to read, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother reading the back before purchasing and gifting it to her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Satanic Verses</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-satanic-verses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 1988 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-satanic-verses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What makes you unique from your contemporaries? How does the culmination of all of your past experiences affect your present choices, and what does that mean about the choices you end up making? Are you destined to fall back into the cycle of what has been, or can you throw everything away and start over, and be able to tell the tale of it all?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are the questions I gathered Mr. Rushdie is trying to ask with the Satanic Verses, among other things (should everything that&amp;rsquo;s said from those you trust be taken face value without question?). What sets a Salman Rushdie book apart from the rest, other than me having to heavily reference a dictionary, is it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In The Distance</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/in-the-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/in-the-distance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While browsing a Strand affiliated pop-up next to central park one spring day not so many weeks ago, a good friend picked this book up and told me it was one of their favorite books. I of course took their opinion seriously, given I&amp;rsquo;ll read, watch, or play just about anything a friend recommends out of principle. It&amp;rsquo;s situations like this very one that makes that principle worth while; this book was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret History</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-secret-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-secret-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What a beautifully written book. Of all the events that transpire, it&amp;rsquo;s the writing that keeps me recommending The Secret History. The story is presented as a mix of a tragedy, a comedy, and a reflection of what powerful influence looks like on impressionable young people. The allure of Julian Morrow sets up a rock that rolls into a boulder, crushing those both caught in the trajectory and the ones behind the push.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thus Spoke Zarathustra</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/thus-spoke-zarathustra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1883 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/thus-spoke-zarathustra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A philosophical endeavor to say the least, Thus Spoke Zarathustra was a tough read and an enlightening one. To start, this is a book I&amp;rsquo;ve owned for many years. As a teenager, I had only a cursory understanding of who Nietzsche was, and was angsty/thought he had all the answers to my questions. It was exactly the opposite; I thought I knew what he was talking about, but I had not even a hint of a clue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind and Truth</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/wind-and-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/wind-and-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previously:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/rhythm-of-war/&#34;&gt;Rhythm of War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really torn on this one. Part of my loved this book, and part of me hated it. I gave it a 4 out of 5, so I must&amp;rsquo;ve liked it more than disliked; I still cannot get over the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s actually done. To be honest, a lot of the reason I gave it a 4 instead of anything lower is that there couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly be the ending I know my heart wants. I want all of my favorite characters to come out not just good, but better, stronger (maybe even Kaladin/Shallan finally happening). Unfortunately, I am a realist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fateful Triangle</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/fateful-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/fateful-triangle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After deep reflection, I still lack the ability to properly give my feedback while remaining professional. This was an incredibly difficult read. Not only was it incredibly lengthy and full of citations and footnotes, it was dense with historical information and new vocabulary. I found myself looking up definitions, synopsis&amp;rsquo; of political parties and events, and having to watch numerous supplemental material to actually follow along. Was this a good thing? I like to think so; it drove me to research a lot on my own, and after 50 or so pages the prose and vocabulary became more tolerable. If only it didn&amp;rsquo;t take another 600 pages/3 months to finish it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhythm of War</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/rhythm-of-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/rhythm-of-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/dawnshard/&#34;&gt;Dawnshard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wow. Completely floored that I was so captivated by this entry. I began as a book 4 hater; it felt like so much had been accomplished in the first three, what else could possibly happen to our cast of characters? Well, it turns out, a lot can happen and change, which is a recurring theme not only throughout this series, but especially in this one. Almost all of our main characters are going through internal and external factors that push them to make decisions, some life-altering, others not so much. What this installation does perfectly I think, is the pain and confusion that comes along with change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dawnshard</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/dawnshard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/dawnshard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/&#34;&gt;Oathbringer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who keeps telling Brando Sando to keep making Novellas, but whoever it is needs to actually &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; them. I really can&amp;rsquo;t justify this being it&amp;rsquo;s own story. Even more than the first, this felt like a different type of filler. Filler with the audacity to be a hardcover.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My issues don&amp;rsquo;t come with the story at all really. I actually enjoyed Rysn, and thought every time she was on the page she felt real. She had valid concerns about being treated as a disabled person in a world not built for one. I loved these parts, and had never even considered before how impossible something like a wheelchair would be in a place without smooth paved roads. I even thought her ability to naturally lead her crew even though she was constantly anxious about it actually made sense. My issues come with how easily digestible this story is, and how it could&amp;rsquo;ve been condensed to take place in the interludes of Rhythm of War.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ring</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1991 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/ring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One that&amp;rsquo;s been on my reading list since I was a kid and saw the dynamic spiral cover, Ring is the original book that inspired the prolific and perfectly-spoofed movie of the same name. Hearing this was a series made me nervous this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great, but I ended up enjoying it at some parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It went by really fast. The main character was the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;/em&gt; dude. Hated how much he clearly did not care about his wife and kids until he put them in danger. Spoiler alert, this guy has the worst gut instincts of all time. He of course becomes friends with the other worst character of all time, and unfortunately make a dynamic duo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/do-androids-dream-of-electric-sheep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1968 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/do-androids-dream-of-electric-sheep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not remembering much from my initial watch of Blade Runner, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect going into this one. I did really enjoy A Scanner Darkly by Dick, so I expected to like this one despite not knowing much. I was not disappointed, and after blowing through this in 2 days I can say I really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The philosophical questions presented combined with the loose answers they provide were interesting and engaging enough for me to think about throughout the read. Trying to find the meaning for the actions and motivations of the characters, just to be given a major thematic question of &amp;ldquo;Should we assign meaning to meaningless things&amp;rdquo; halfway through got me good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edgedancer</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/edgedancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/edgedancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definitely a novella that took me too long to finish, and not really because I was enjoying it. More so because I didn&amp;rsquo;t love Lift as a character. I was actually going to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t hate their childish behavior, but typing that out I had a gut feeling I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; like how childish Lift was. Maybe that was her point, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp onto the story. Wendel, her spren, being a Squidward-type that doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to go anywhere or do anything was a nice contrast, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help feel sorry that we find out the character Wendel could have been with died in one of the earlier books, and was a more interesting character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oathbringer</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Holy Moly. What a ride. This book took &lt;em&gt;FOREVER&lt;/em&gt; to finish. Exactly 3 months and a day to be exact. But it was so worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A true continuation from &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt;, this book follows the logical progression from where that book left off and really begins to open up the world. There are still lots of secrets left to unfold (Who is Wit? Who is the Cremling God that Lift meets in Edgedancer? What&amp;rsquo;s going to happen with Renarin? How is Odium going to exploit Taravangian? WHY DOESN&amp;rsquo;T KALADIN AND SHALLAN GET TOGETHER???) which has me very excited for the next two books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Road</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/the-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modified: July 14 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I finished The Road a few days ago and I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected fondly on the experience. Slow burn isn&amp;rsquo;t the word I&amp;rsquo;d use; perhaps a slow agonizing death. Because by the end, I was emotionally exhausted. It asks a lot of you. Sit through the gray, dim world that the story takes place in. Hope to some God the end is worth it. In my opinion, I think it was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words of Radiance</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modified: July 02 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I finished Words of Radiance two days ago, and it initially got a 4 out of 5. I loved the book. I really did, and was invested from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took me about 3 weeks (3 weeks and 3 days says Goodreads) and it really flew by. I enjoyed tackling such a huge tome of a novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The characters were awesome, even if I felt like the interlude characters could have been longer to make them a bit more memorable. I only remember maybe one of them, and it was Lift cause they had a really cool attitude and wanted to just eat some good food.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Are Not Expected To Understand This</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/you-are-not-expected-to-understand-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/you-are-not-expected-to-understand-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modified: July 26 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;26 short essays on the pieces/lines of code that shaped the modern understanding of computer science.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6/3/24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Halfway through, I think some of the stories are interesting. Some of the articles don&amp;rsquo;t go as deep as I think they could/should; some bring up gender/race for seemingly no reason&amp;hellip;others actually delve deeper into the politics of it encouragingly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrpointing.com/notes/topics-im-interested-in/&#34;&gt;Topics I&amp;rsquo;m Interested In&lt;/a&gt; because of this book pretty much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
