<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fantasy on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fantasy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fantasy on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fantasy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Edgedancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/edgedancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/edgedancer/</guid>
      <description>Previous: Words of Radiance&#xA;Definitely a novella that took me too long to finish, and not really because I was enjoying it. More so because I didn&amp;rsquo;t love Lift as a character. I was actually going to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t hate their childish behavior, but typing that out I had a gut feeling I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself.&#xA;I really didn&amp;rsquo;t like how childish Lift was. Maybe that was her point, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp onto the story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oathbringer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/oathbringer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/oathbringer/</guid>
      <description>Holy Moly. What a ride. This book took FOREVER to finish. Exactly 3 months and a day to be exact. But it was so worth it.&#xA;A true continuation from Words of Radiance, this book follows the logical progression from where that book left off and really begins to open up the world. There are still lots of secrets left to unfold (Who is Wit? Who is the Cremling God that Lift meets in Edgedancer?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words of Radiance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/words-of-radiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/words-of-radiance/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 02 2024&#xA;I finished Words of Radiance two days ago, and it initially got a 4 out of 5. I loved the book. I really did, and was invested from start to finish.&#xA;It took me about 3 weeks (3 weeks and 3 days says Goodreads) and it really flew by. I enjoyed tackling such a huge tome of a novel.&#xA;The characters were awesome, even if I felt like the interlude characters could have been longer to make them a bit more memorable.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
