<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fantasy on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fantasy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fantasy on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fantasy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dawnshard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/dawnshard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/dawnshard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/&#34;&gt;Oathbringer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who keeps telling Brando Sando to keep making Novellas, but whoever it is needs to actually &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; them. I really can&amp;rsquo;t justify this being it&amp;rsquo;s own story. Even more than the first, this felt like a different type of filler. Filler with the audacity to be a hardcover.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My issues don&amp;rsquo;t come with the story at all really. I actually enjoyed Rysn, and thought every time she was on the page she felt real. She had valid concerns about being treated as a disabled person in a world not built for one. I loved these parts, and had never even considered before how impossible something like a wheelchair would be in a place without smooth paved roads. I even thought her ability to naturally lead her crew even though she was constantly anxious about it actually made sense. My issues come with how easily digestible this story is, and how it could&amp;rsquo;ve been condensed to take place in the interludes of Rhythm of War.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edgedancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/edgedancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/edgedancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definitely a novella that took me too long to finish, and not really because I was enjoying it. More so because I didn&amp;rsquo;t love Lift as a character. I was actually going to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t hate their childish behavior, but typing that out I had a gut feeling I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; like how childish Lift was. Maybe that was her point, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp onto the story. Wendel, her spren, being a Squidward-type that doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to go anywhere or do anything was a nice contrast, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help feel sorry that we find out the character Wendel could have been with died in one of the earlier books, and was a more interesting character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oathbringer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/oathbringer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Holy Moly. What a ride. This book took &lt;em&gt;FOREVER&lt;/em&gt; to finish. Exactly 3 months and a day to be exact. But it was so worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A true continuation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt;, this book follows the logical progression from where that book left off and really begins to open up the world. There are still lots of secrets left to unfold (Who is Wit? Who is the Cremling God that Lift meets in Edgedancer? What&amp;rsquo;s going to happen with Renarin? How is Odium going to exploit Taravangian? WHY DOESN&amp;rsquo;T KALADIN AND SHALLAN GET TOGETHER???) which has me very excited for the next two books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words of Radiance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/books/words-of-radiance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modified: July 02 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I finished Words of Radiance two days ago, and it initially got a 4 out of 5. I loved the book. I really did, and was invested from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took me about 3 weeks (3 weeks and 3 days says Goodreads) and it really flew by. I enjoyed tackling such a huge tome of a novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The characters were awesome, even if I felt like the interlude characters could have been longer to make them a bit more memorable. I only remember maybe one of them, and it was Lift cause they had a really cool attitude and wanted to just eat some good food.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
