<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Horror on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>https://mrpointing.com/tags/horror/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Horror on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mrpointing.com/tags/horror/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perfume</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/perfume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1985 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/perfume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m super torn about this one. A beautifully written book about an man who commits horrible, atrocious acts that are unredeemable from a moral standpoint. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to even dissect without getting right into it, so let&amp;rsquo;s just do that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all, again, the way this author writes is right up my alley. It was engaging, kept me coming back even when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I wanted too. The world he draws you into feels so palpable, especially considering the main sense this book tries to make you feel is scent. It was enthralling hearing the ways he would describe the world and activities the main character participated in. Most of the book is like this, and a good amount of the exposition doesn&amp;rsquo;t even really come off as horror, and more classical. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be more upset by that considering I only started reading this for the horror aspect, but I actually ended up loving it for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ring</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1991 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/books/ring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One that&amp;rsquo;s been on my reading list since I was a kid and saw the dynamic spiral cover, Ring is the original book that inspired the prolific and perfectly-spoofed movie of the same name. Hearing this was a series made me nervous this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great, but I ended up enjoying it at some parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It went by really fast. The main character was the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;/em&gt; dude. Hated how much he clearly did not care about his wife and kids until he put them in danger. Spoiler alert, this guy has the worst gut instincts of all time. He of course becomes friends with the other worst character of all time, and unfortunately make a dynamic duo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
