<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Mr. Pointing</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Mr. Pointing</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Blender Donut Tutorial</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blender-donut-tutorial/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blender-donut-tutorial/</guid>
            <description>Link to video series
Why Do I Want to Learn Blender? My uncle is a huge inspiration in my life and career. I always admired his artistic ability, always drawing my favorite super heroes and other cool pieces. He ended working full time as a graphic design artist, and has been making killer 3D animations for years.
This is another way of integrating what things I love, and also possibly picking up a new hobby.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B0J27sf9N1Y">Link</a> to video series</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="why-do-i-want-to-learn-blender">Why Do I Want to Learn Blender?</h1>
<p>My uncle is a huge inspiration in my life and career. I always admired his artistic ability, always drawing my favorite super heroes and other cool pieces. He ended working full time as a graphic design artist, and has been making killer 3D animations for years.</p>
<p>This is another way of integrating what things I love, and also possibly picking up a new hobby. Let&rsquo;s see how this goes.</p>
<h2 id="part-1-introduction">Part 1: Introduction</h2>
<p>Basic installation and walkthrough of getting started. Most importantly, how to add things into your scene, <code>Ctrl+A</code>. Super useful shortcut, and for the most part we are going to work with <strong>meshes.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Render View Mode</strong> can be toggled on to include directional lighting, which can be set by the position of the camera. More details on moving around and moving the camera are in the video.</p>
<p><strong>Renders</strong>, or detailed stills of your camera view, can be made with <code>F12</code>.</p>
<p>A good cheat to move the camera with camera view enabled (<code>Numpad 0</code>) is to use <code>n</code> to open properties, select the <code>View</code> tab, then choose the <code>Lock Camera to View</code> option. This will move your camera to where your view is.</p>
<p>To change the color of meshes, you should add a <strong>material</strong> to it, on the right side bar with the object selected. From there, you can select a color from the scale.</p>
<p>Hitting <code>s</code> on an object will activate the <em>Scale</em> property, allowing you to quickly alter the objects shape along the axis.</p>
<p>You also, when viewing through your camera lens, might want to quickly move something around, or rotate it. You can hit <code>r</code> to activate the <em>Rotate</em> tool, which will let you rotate your object around in place.</p>
<h2 id="part-2-basic-modeling">Part 2: Basic Modeling</h2>
<p>To make our donut, we should use the most donut-like starting object; the Torus. From there, we should edit the properties using <code>F9</code> to scale it accordingly. We could use a high major and minor segment count, but doing so will actually make our life harder down the road. It is easier to scale up than it is to scale down, and there are some neat tools that we can use to make it look like our low poly object is a higher resolution. For now, we can se our major to 32, and minor to 12.</p>
<p>To start with those tools to help us fake it till we make it, we can right click and hit <strong>Shade Smooth</strong>, which will make our object look a lot nicer. We should also add a <em>Modifier</em>, which will help our object smooth out even more. The little wrench icon in the bottom right after clicking on an object will allow you to add a <strong>Subdivision Surface</strong>, which essentially exponentially add details.</p>
<p>Now that our object has the shape we like, we can deform it a bit to make it more realistic by hitting <code>Tab</code> to open up the vertex viewer, then click on a vertex to move it around. Moving one by itself though doesn&rsquo;t look great; you should use <strong>Proportional Editing</strong>, which can be turned on with the tiny circles button, and move multiple parts of your object in unison to get a more natural looking movement. If you want to select an entire edge, <code>Alt+Left Click</code> to select.</p>
<h2 id="part-3-modeling-the-icing">Part 3: Modeling the Icing</h2>
<p>Lots going on in this one, so be prepared for definitions. Without doing this as a frame of reference, none of this makes any sense.</p>
<p>Instead of creating a whole new shape, we know we just the top part of a donut, and that can become our icing texture. You can duplicate any object with <code>Shift+D</code>.</p>
<p>Now, you clearly don&rsquo;t want the icing covering the entire thing, or you might as well not include it at all. You&rsquo;ll have to select the entire bottom of the object and delete it. An easy way to do this is by using the toggle x-ray tool <code>Alt+z</code> to see through and select all the vertices at a time instead of just the one side your camera is looking at. Then, delete all vertices.</p>
<p>The icing looks pretty bad, since Blender is trying to render two faces on top of one another. To avoid this, we should try to keep them as close together as we can allow. To start, we should add a <em>solidify</em> modifier, and set the <em>offset</em> and <em>inner crease</em> to 1, and the thickness to something like 0.025. The inner crease will help later by making your icing look like it&rsquo;s more attached to the donut.</p>
<p>Sometimes your modifier will hide your mesh from view, in which case you need to toggle the view in the right side next to the modifier&rsquo;s name.</p>
<p>To actually drag out the icing and have it not clip into the donut, you need to do a few things. First thing, with the icing selected, you need to <strong>snap</strong> it (<code>Shift+Tab</code>) using <em>face project</em>, but that&rsquo;s not all. You&rsquo;ll also have to apply a subdivision modifier. It should already have one, so click the down arrow next the named subdivision modifier and click apply. This should make more faces appear in edit mode.</p>
<p>Sometimes you want to make part of your mesh unedited, or left alone. In our case, we don&rsquo;t want to affect the icing in the middle of our donut. We should select all of the vertices (<code>Alt-Click</code> them) and hide them with <code>h</code>. Now, you should be able to drag the icing around and make it more icing like.</p>
<p>To make specific portions droop down more without making the faces clip, you could elongate it with <code>e</code> and <code>click</code> for each new portion.</p>
<h2 id="part-4-sculpting">Part 4: Sculpting</h2>
<p>Now is a good time to check your icing to look for any issues. You could move each vertex individually if you have any clipping, or you could use a modifier. This time, we have the <strong>shrink-wrap</strong> modifier, used to attach one object to another and smooth out the connection. If you apply it <em>after</em> the subdivision it&rsquo;ll give you issues, so make sure to drag it to the top then hit <code>Apply</code>.</p>
<p>Now, if we wanted to add in detail that comes along with icing like the ability for icing to pile at the ends/bottom of the donut, currently we couldn&rsquo;t grab any vertex and change it to look nice at all. First, we have to <em>apply</em> our <strong>solidify</strong> modifier, so we can actually get the 3D mesh. Then, <em>apply</em> our <strong>subdivision</strong> modifier with a viewport resolution of 2. This will actually let us edit in the version it&rsquo;s going to look like.</p>
<p>Now that we&rsquo;re set up, we can use the <em><strong>Sculpt</strong></em> tool, which acts like a brush to do certain elements faster than individually clicking each vertex.</p>
<p>Technically these next few including Sculpt are brushes, so that&rsquo;s how I&rsquo;ll be referring to them. The next useful one is <strong>Grab</strong>, that works like a finger to push your objects as if they were clay.</p>
<p>Making a <strong>Mask</strong> is telling Blender an area you <em>don&rsquo;t</em> want to affect; by default, when doing something like <strong>Inflating</strong> (or making objects larger) you would inflate everything except what&rsquo;s chosen in the mask. If you want to select the mask, you would need to invert it.</p>
<p>The <strong>Smooth</strong> brush allows you to easily smooth out textures. You should do this anytime you have any <em>artifacting</em>.</p>
<h2 id="part-5-shading">Part 5: Shading</h2>
<p>Time to add some colors to things. I noticed that in my process of creating the donut, I have a few more vertices than him in the viewport, so I might have added another layer of complexity. I&rsquo;m also getting some jagged edges in rendering, which I might have to add another layer for just that later.</p>
<p>For now, add the <em>material</em> for color to the icing and the donut. We&rsquo;re going to have to make a table for our donut to sit on, so we should use the <strong>plane</strong> mesh that will act as our table. Scale it out to an appropriate size. The problem now is that if we move our donut, the icing won&rsquo;t follow. To avoid this, make the icing a child of the donut. Click the icing, then <code>Ctrl</code> click the donut, and hit <code>Ctrl+P</code>.</p>
<p>This part is pretty complicated so strap in. We want to add a texture to the plane. Let&rsquo;s do a Marble countertop as our goal. We can go grab a random marble from this guy&rsquo;s website (have to pay for most but a good amount are free) and we can apply it to the plane, by clicking the yellow circle next to the material&rsquo;s color and choosing Image.</p>
<p>To me it looked great, but he pointed out that the marble was really flat, so we&rsquo;re going to have to modify a little more. Instead of using the tool bar on the right, we&rsquo;re going to go to an entirely different area called <em><strong>Shading</strong></em>.  This will give us more direct control over our elements via the Node system, which shows a workflow our how our object is modified from start to finish (left to right).</p>
<p>Refer to the video for this part because it is hard to explain writing it out, but you need to create two more nodes, one for the Roughness and one for Normal (which will actually provide more textures). There&rsquo;s some funny stuff with colors going on that he doesn&rsquo;t outright explain, so I&rsquo;d rather not butcher it. Essentially there are some settings that have to be changed around color for Blender to display the textures correctly.</p>
<p>After those are done, there&rsquo;s one filter we have to add before we attach the normal mapping to the plane. We need a <strong>Normal Map</strong>, which will provide those bumps, scratches, and smudges on the countertop.</p>
<p>To get an even more realistic feel for our donut, we can isolate it (click it and hit <code>/</code>) and notice there is no whiter ring along the outside of our donut. Real donuts have this because they&rsquo;re cooked less on the outer-most rim.</p>
<p>We can add that by clicking on our donut and creating an <em>Image Texture</em>. First go to the <strong>Texture Paint</strong> tab and go to materials. Click the yellow circle next to color to select image texture, then select <code>New</code>. Call it <code>donut_base.png</code> or something, and set some default colors with the default resolution. On the left side of the screen, on the photo icon, click the <code>donut_base</code> image. Now, we can paint directly onto our mesh. Mess around with the colors and the brush levels to get the type of look you desire.</p>
<h2 id="part-6-geometry-nodes">Part 6: Geometry Nodes</h2>
<p>We&rsquo;re going to start creating our sprinkles by creating new <em>Geometry Nodes</em>. There is a heading tab we have to switch too, and we can generally get rid of the spreadsheet on the top left. Now with our icing selected, click &ldquo;New&rdquo;. Geometry Nodes are actually modifiers, so you should also see a new modifier on the bottom right.</p>
<p>Now, what we&rsquo;re actually doing here is giving our mesh objects more options by choosing different ways of manipulating our mesh, then passing them into our node system. Once there, anywhere in Blender I can now easily access whatever changes I set up to make. For the sprinkles, we want random points across our mesh, so use <code>Shift+A</code> to go to <code>Point</code>, then <code>Distribute Points on Face</code>. This node should go between the connection of input and output (into mesh).</p>
<p>This is only halfway there, however. What actually happened here was that it took the icing mesh, made it these points, and fed it back to us. This <em>isn&rsquo;t</em> what we want, since we want both the mesh and these new points. This is where we use <code>Shift+A</code> to <code>Geometry</code>, then use the <code>Join Geometry</code> features to connect the distribution node we just made to the output. We will also have to drag a line from the input into the join node to actually create that join.</p>
<p>Making the sprinkle is really easy, just use <code>Shift+A</code> to create a UV Sphere Mesh. Since it will be used many times over and will be small, we can make it low resolution at 12 segments and 8 rings, and a size of <code>0.01 meters</code> . Since we&rsquo;ve created our sphere, we can easily use the top right menu to drag it into our Geometry Nodes work area for our icing.</p>
<p>To get this sphere to be represented by the node we have creating points on our icing, we can use another node called <code>Instance on Points</code>. This should go between your distribution node and join node. This instance node replaces the nodes with whatever is passed into it. So, we know we just dragged in our sphere mesh, drag from the geometry out on the sphere node to the instance input on the instance node.</p>
<p>If you increase the density, you&rsquo;ll notice quickly the sprinkles are so random they&rsquo;re inside of one another. This can be avoided by using <em>Poisson Disk</em> distribution, which gives you the ability to change the distance minimum between points. Set to a value of 0.012 is a good start, as going too far apart will look a little unrealistic.</p>
<p>We also have a ton of sprinkles everywhere, any I mean everywhere. Even on the inside of our mesh. This is going to cause our machine to work harder to render it, even though there are things we&rsquo;re not even seeing. To avoid this we use <strong>Weight Painting</strong>. On the top left, hit the Object View drop down and choose Weight Paint. Your donut should turn blue; just for the sake of starting, draw a circle on top of your icing.</p>
<p>You should notice the circle you painted is a bright red, with other green and yellow around the edges. This is going to act as our area of effect for our distribution of sprinkles. Donuts naturally have more sprinkles in the part dipped into the sprinkle tray, which is more often than not a perfect circle on the top most part of the donut. Creating a thick ring with some imperfect spots here and there will do us justice, but we have to call it into action.</p>
<p>First up, make sure the paint brush stroke you made was only on the front of your mesh by using the <code>front faces only</code> option under the advanced drop down on your object view tool bar. Your new brushed circle exists as a data object, and we should name it something useful (we&rsquo;re about to use it). Then, from your density factor input option on your distribution node, drag out and select named attribute. Then, you&rsquo;re going to choose the name you just made for your sprinkles.</p>
<p>If we made a duplicate of our donut and changed the Geometry Nodes values directly from the menu nodes, it&rsquo;ll change both. However, if you want some option to be specific to each object, you can drag any input out into the origin input node, so each will have it in their properties.</p>
<p>If you look at the properties of our donut, you&rsquo;ll notice it&rsquo;s around 1.2 meters across. That&rsquo;s about 4 feet long in America, which is huge for a donut. To fix this, we have to scale it down. Select everything and hit <code>s</code> and use <code>Ctrl</code> to go down by constant values. if we&rsquo;re at 1.2 meters, 0.12 would be more accurate.</p>
<p>The scale isn&rsquo;t applied yet though. Select everything, <code>Ctrl+A</code>, and hit <code>Apply Scale</code>. You&rsquo;ll notice it works if your sprinkles look messed up. You&rsquo;ll have to massively increase your density for sprinkles. You can either increase it by around x10,000 or use a math multiplier node between.</p>
<h2 id="part-7-long-sprinkles">Part 7: Long Sprinkles</h2>
<p>Right off the bat, we have our first conversation about the 3D cursor. The 3D cursor is where any newly created object will be placed. We want to see our sprinkle so we should probably move it to the plane (<code>Alt+Right Click</code>).</p>
<p>The long sprinkle is a cylinder. Bring it down to the smallest size, then just 12 vertices. I had some trouble moving the sprinkles around, for whatever reason the mesh would zoom into the plane if my cursor was over the plane. In his video it worked fine, not sure what setting I had on that made that happen.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll need to round out the ends of the sprinkle, so hit <code>Tab</code> and <em>face select</em> (3) to select the top and bottom face, and use <code>Ctrl+B</code> to apply a bevel. Scroll up on the mouse wheel a bit to apply more geometry, but not too much. Then You have a nice rounder edge. Don&rsquo;t forget to apply smooth shading.</p>
<p>Use duplicate to make another sprinkle, and we&rsquo;ll create our medium size. Hit <code>Tab</code> and enter vertex select. Select the top vertices, then <code>G</code>, and <code>X</code> to move along the X axes. Do this again for your large sprinkle. We also want one more of the large sprinkle so we can bend it.</p>
<p>To create more geometry to enable a bend, we&rsquo;ll need a loop cut. Hit <code>Ctrl+R</code> and scroll up to use about 8 cuts. We could bend it now, but there&rsquo;s actually a nice modifier that will accomplish that for us. Hit modifier and search for a <em>Simple Deform</em> modifier. Select <code>Bend</code> and it&rsquo;ll create really easily maneuverable bending motions in whatever angle you&rsquo;d like.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ll notice the bend is centered at the bottom of the sprinkle. That&rsquo;s because that&rsquo;s where our origin point is, the little yellow/orange circle that&rsquo;s on every mesh object. We should move this to the center of all of our sprinkles. Use <code>Ctrl</code> to select all your sprinkles, then use <code>Right Click</code> to select <code>Set Origin</code>, then select <code>Origin to Geometry</code>.</p>
<p>Now to help for getting the sprinkles onto the icing, we need to put them in a collection in the top right. Once in a folder, duplicate the donut and make sure to click the two next to the icings geometry nodes modifier, so each donut is separate.</p>
<p>Then, hop on over to Geometry Nodes. Take out the current node attached to the <code>instance</code> path on the <code>Instance on Points</code> node. That was our round sprinkles, now we need our long ones. Take the collection we made and drag it into the Geometry Nodes environment. Then attach that to where the round sprinkles were. Hit Reset Children, Separate Children, and Pick Instance.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Day 31 - Summary</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/day-31---summary/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/day-31---summary/</guid>
            <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I worked on this project for 30 days. The growth has been fantastic, and I should be proud of all that I was able to accomplish. If this is true, why do I feel a pit in my stomach when I think about this project? If I did such a good job, why do I feel like such crap?
To be honest, the more I worked on this the more I understood why it takes teams of people to produce applications.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>I can&rsquo;t believe I worked on this project for 30 days. The growth has been fantastic, and I should be proud of all that I was able to accomplish. If this is true, why do I feel a pit in my stomach when I think about this project? If I did such a good job, why do I feel like such crap?</p>
<p>To be honest, the more I worked on this the more I understood why it takes teams of people to produce applications. I know there are gurus out there who can solo develop their ideas, but wow I never realized how <em>not</em> like that I am. I enjoyed every part of the development process, yet the more I saw of the road ahead of me to actually make this usable? That is what really scared me.</p>
<p>When I look at my work, it&rsquo;s difficult to not see all the faults. CSS is not my strong suit, and I know I cut corners in some areas (please don&rsquo;t resize my windows ಥ_ಥ). I made separate pages for things that could have easily been one page. I ended up ditching an entire process and offloaded in onto Calendly, which takes away from the entire point of the project if you think about it too much. The more I produced, the more inadequate I felt. I felt like there was more I should have done, more time I should have spent learning x or practicing y.</p>
<p>This is the wrong way of thinking about it. I have a lot to be thankful for, and I&rsquo;m happy I was able to say I worked on something I&rsquo;m passionate about. I&rsquo;m walking away from this project with a better understanding of API&rsquo;s, writing and handling requests, storing images via SQLite, sending emails with Yagmail, actually using JavaScript for the first time, and much more.</p>
<p>If anything, seeing how much I didn&rsquo;t know motivated me to just learn <strong>more</strong>. I started going through the <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/front-end/the-odin-project/fundamental-css-properties/">Odin Project</a>, finally admitting to myself that yeah, I should probably learn JavaScript. I started looking into responsive design and best practices of working on the front-end of applications. The structure of working on my project alone has changed my perspective on my daily structure; I&rsquo;ve started journaling to hold myself more accountable and have an outlet for my emotions and frantic thoughts.</p>
<p>I do feel sad that I&rsquo;m walking away from these 30 days, and I&rsquo;m no where near a master level engineer, and I don&rsquo;t have a fully functional project. Was that the reason I started though? Not really.</p>
<p>I started these 30 days because I wanted to see if I could do it. No, the days weren&rsquo;t consecutive, but why does it have to be? I don&rsquo;t have to place arbitrary rules on things I design for myself. Had I been so serious about it, I likely would have never made it to day 30.</p>
<p>I started these 30 days because I wanted to be a good influence on my students, and show them that they should be proud to work on something, and make progress on their own creations.</p>
<p>I started these 30 days because I love my wife, and what better way to show that love than make something she can use in her professional life.</p>
<p>The reasons outweigh the reflective feelings. The longer you stare into the abyss, the more the abyss looks back (or something like that). I&rsquo;m never going to be done learning, and that&rsquo;s okay. To think there is some summit to reach where you&rsquo;ll find all the masters sitting and waiting for you is a false flag. You&rsquo;re never going to get there, but neither will the masters. The journey of learning is an ongoing process, and as long as you love the process, you&rsquo;ll never stop learning.</p>
<p>If you haven&rsquo;t already checked it out, please give my project a look at! <a href="http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-1/">Day 1</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>20 Textbooks</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20-textbooks/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20-textbooks/</guid>
            <description>For 2025, I want to read and document my notes on Obsidian for 20 different textbooks. I acquired most of these throughout 2024 (thank you Humble Bundle!), and I thought why not put my money where my mouth is and actually use all the books I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased. Below is a list that I&amp;rsquo;ll keep updated, as well as a link to their inevitable notes.
1. Learning Git 2. Deep Learning - Math 3.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>For 2025, I want to read and document my notes on Obsidian for 20 different textbooks. I acquired most of these throughout 2024 (thank you Humble Bundle!), and I thought why not put my money where my mouth is and actually use all the books I&rsquo;ve purchased. Below is a list that I&rsquo;ll keep updated, as well as a link to their inevitable notes.</p>
<ul>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> 1. <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/learning-git/learning-git---chapter-1/">Learning Git</a></li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> 2. <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/deep-learning/deep-learning---preface--chapter-1/">Deep Learning - Math</a></li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> 3. <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/grokking-algorithms/grokking-algorithms---chapter-1/">Grokking Algorithms</a></li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 4. <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/programming-in-lua/the-basics/programming-in-lua---chapter-1/">Learning Lua</a></li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 5. Learning Modern Linux</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 6. Real World Python</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 7. Impractical Python Projects</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 8. Foundations of Information Security</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 9. Penetration Testing</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 10. Python for DevOps</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 11. Fast API</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 12. The Shape of Data</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 13. Deep Learning: A Visual Approach</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 14. Practical Linux Systems Administration</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 15. Efficient Linux at the Command Line</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 16. Linux Basics for Hackers</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 17. Cyberjutsu</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 18. Network Programmability &amp; Automation</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 19. Docker Up &amp; Running</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 20. Learning DevSecOps</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Teaching with Obsidian</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/teaching-with-obsidian/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/teaching-with-obsidian/</guid>
            <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s obvious to everyone, but as a teacher I noticed that students do not know how to take notes. At best a student is writing something down, albeit not very good notes. Most are not taking any notes at all.
This is a small band-aid fix, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start implementing Obsidian as a minor section of my curriculum this year. Online notes are not a replacement for good handwritten note-taking, but for my Computer Science Honors kids it&amp;rsquo;s a good place to store code from lessons and start to think about what&amp;rsquo;s really important.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>I&rsquo;m not sure if it&rsquo;s obvious to everyone, but as a teacher I noticed that students do not know how to take notes. At best a student is writing something down, albeit not very good notes. Most are not taking any notes at all.</p>
<p>This is a small band-aid fix, but I&rsquo;m going to start implementing Obsidian as a minor section of my curriculum this year. Online notes are not a replacement for good handwritten note-taking, but for my Computer Science Honors kids it&rsquo;s a good place to store code from lessons and start to think about what&rsquo;s really important.</p>
<p>There is no bad way to take notes, but taking no notes at all is certainly a worse alternative. They should be having fun and be excited to try something new that&rsquo;s beneficial to them. I&rsquo;m also stepping away from letting my kids use PyCharm&rsquo;s code completion since they get too reliant on it, and will devote a few weeks on just getting more familiar with <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/pycharm-ide-features/">using an IDE</a>.</p>
<p>I only just started, but I&rsquo;ve been working on going through the <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/obsidian/obsidian-help/obsidian-help---preface/">Obsidian help documentation</a>. It&rsquo;s a great way to structure a lesson plan and get&rsquo;s the kids writing right away. I don&rsquo;t know if I want to enforce a structure around note taking to get some grade to keep them doing it, or letting them just do there thing after the lessons are over and see if it sticks. Either way this year is looking to be a really exciting year!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Explaining my Obsidian to Hugo Workflow</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/explaining-my-obsidian-to-hugo-workflow/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/explaining-my-obsidian-to-hugo-workflow/</guid>
            <description>Where We Left Off I was just able to get my website viewable for the first time in Hugo&amp;rsquo;s draft view. I worked through the formatting errors that my Hugo theme wasn&amp;rsquo;t compatible with, and everything is looking good.
Implementing Git was also incredibly simple. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Git, you can start by reading my analysis of a beginner Git textbook. Since Hugo requires you using a separate directory for content, just initialize a new repo in your directory, connect it to a GitHub repo, and you&amp;rsquo;re off to the races.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2 id="where-we-left-off">Where We Left Off</h2>
<p>I was just able to get my <a href="https://mrpointing.com">website</a> viewable for the first time in Hugo&rsquo;s draft view. I worked through the formatting errors that my Hugo theme wasn&rsquo;t compatible with, and everything is looking good.</p>
<p>Implementing Git was also incredibly simple. If you don&rsquo;t know anything about Git, you can start by reading my analysis of a beginner <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/learning-git/learning-git---chapter-1/">Git textbook</a>. Since Hugo requires you using a separate directory for content, just initialize a new repo in your directory, connect it to a GitHub repo, and you&rsquo;re off to the races.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s going to determine what shows up on your site is what&rsquo;s committed to your GitHub repo, so it&rsquo;s a good idea to make sure your content looks good before you make your commit. Considering you have (and if you haven&rsquo;t, you should) read my quick dive into the structure of <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/hugo/getting-started-with-hugo/">hugo</a>, you know that before committing anything to our repo, we clear out the <code>public</code> directory, call <code>hugo</code> to build our site, then use basic Git commands to push to your main branch.</p>
<h2 id="fixing-my-problems">Fixing My Problems</h2>
<p>I did have one major issue though; now that I had spent a few hours fixing and finding out all of the unique issues within my markdown files, did I want to do this procedure EVERYTIME I wanted to update my site? No thank you. Now that I&rsquo;m using GitHub, if I were to use Obsidian to Hugo it would end up writing over all of the syntax I just finished editing.</p>
<p>The main problems were that:</p>
<ol>
<li>By default, Hugo doesn&rsquo;t support LaTeX inline math like Obsidian does, so using dollar signs to denote math doesn&rsquo;t work</li>
<li>Images are usually Excalidraw files, which are also markdown files, so Obsidian to Hugo links them like normal markdown instead of images.</li>
</ol>
<p>I use both often enough to have this be a concern for me, So I ended up structuring my workflow like so:</p>

    <img src="/images/mr_pointing_workflow.png"  alt="mr_pointing_workflow"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>Like I mentioned in my last post, using <code>draft</code> is not only essential to using Hugo, but overall using it as an Obsidian property relieved the headache that was starting to develop. <code>draft</code> became a small check-box on the top of all of my Obsidian notes; if I know I&rsquo;m going to edit it and want to post it later I&rsquo;ll check it to be <code>True</code>, or leave it unchecked as <code>False</code> if I don&rsquo;t want to transfer it over.</p>
<p>Since Obsidian to Hugo allows for filters, I added a filter to only grab markdown files in my vault where <code>draft: True</code> (I also added a basic <code>print</code> statement to give myself a convenient list of all the files it picked up so I don&rsquo;t miss any). Now I don&rsquo;t have to keep a running list of all the files I need to update before pushing to production, I can just let the drafts pile up, collect them at the end of the week, test, then deploy.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Starting My Website</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/starting-my-website/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/starting-my-website/</guid>
            <description>As a first official post, why not start at the beginning. I want to quickly go over how I started, my motivations, and the first issues I ran into. The footnotes will reference all of the articles and videos I watched that helped contribute to how it works today.
Components Obsidian Git/GitHub Hugo Cloudflare How I Started Regarding Obsdian, I began writing as if I were dictating to my students.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>As a first official post, why not start at the beginning. I want to quickly go over how I started, my motivations, and the first issues I ran into. The footnotes will reference all of the articles and videos I watched that helped contribute to how it works today.</p>
<h2 id="components">Components</h2>
<ul>
<li>Obsidian</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mr-pointing/website">Git/GitHub</a></li>
<li><a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a></li>
<li>Cloudflare</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="how-i-started">How I Started</h2>
<p>Regarding Obsdian, I began writing as if I were dictating to my students. Instead of overthinking the design of the site and never making content, I just started taking notes. I started with going through a <a href="http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/python-tutorial/the-python-tutorial-notes---chapter-1-2-and-3/">python tutorial</a>, and kept branching out to what it is now. The flow and structure has changed numerous times already; I&rsquo;m sure in a few weeks it will be a little different.</p>
<p>Most tutorials I read online start at the beginning, and show how to start with a fresh blog. Assuming you understand Hugo (and if you don&rsquo;t you should read the articles in the footnotes), I&rsquo;m going to start right after where the quick-start leaves you.</p>
<h2 id="making-a-blog-from-an-existing-vault">Making a Blog From an Existing Vault</h2>
<p>So I tried the <a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/">tutorial</a> on my laptop before bringing it over to my main machine, so I started on a good note.</p>
<p>I set up my Hugo site to live in a directory named <code>/mr_pointing</code>, and started with the theme <a href="https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng/">hello-friend-ng</a>. I decided to add it as a submodule, which will come back to haunt me.</p>
<p>I dropped my first Obsidian file in, and&hellip;it looked terrible. A lot of my files contain code, math, images, etc. I was not prepared for it to look so different. And it was still just the first file!</p>
<p>After some Googling I came across <a href="https://github.com/devidw/obsidian-to-hugo">Obsidian to Hugo</a>. This would help immensely, by taking my current markdown files and replacing the Obsidian specific syntax with Hugo syntax. Awesome, but this made me realize I had two issues to deal with.</p>
<p>The first issue was simple, I had no frontmatter, or properties, so I had to add some to all of my existing 60 or so files. I used Templater, an Obsidian plugin, to create template headers with properties set, with <code>tags</code>, <code>title</code>, <code>date</code>, etc. Hugo uses the property <code>draft</code> to tell if something should be published or not. This is how I decided to start building my workflow, but we&rsquo;ll get back to that later.</p>
<p>My second issue arose when I started making the properties; I couldn&rsquo;t nail how to get the date settings right. I was already having problems with using Templater&rsquo;s file dot method to grab the modified time and not updating (<code>&lt;$ tp.file.last_modified_date %&gt;</code>), which was getting frustrating. That eventually led me to using Update on Edit, another Obsidian Plugin, to add in a better last modified property. I already had <code>date</code> that works with my Theme&rsquo;s posting format, so I&rsquo;m happy.</p>
<p>I should have all my problems solved right? Wrong.</p>
<p>Running <code>hugo server -D</code> wouldn&rsquo;t even start the website. I had about 30-40 errors, that ranged in difficulty. I want to do a video that goes deeper in on that, so stay tuned for that. Going over all of the little instance cases are worth it, especially if your workflow looks similar to mine. Let&rsquo;s cut to the chase and point out the biggest issue - Obsidian to Hugo&rsquo;s formatting and how it&rsquo;s not perfect.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t think this is the fault of the tool, my files weren&rsquo;t set up well to start with. So most of the issues came from it picking up references to notes that didn&rsquo;t exist, and images it couldn&rsquo;t reach. Turns out, the theme I&rsquo;m using gives you a way to call images in the docs (it took me way too long to find that&hellip;).</p>
<p>After fixing all of the issues, it finally worked. I now have my site running on my local machine! Time to start on the hosting side. But first, Git.</p>
<p>I made my first commit to my main <a href="https://github.com/mr-pointing/website">repository</a>.</p>
<h2 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h2>
<p><a href="https://developers.cloudflare.com/pages/framework-guides/deploy-a-hugo-site/">Cloudflare Hugo Help Page</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/">Mischa van der Berg</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://santacloud.dev/posts/creating-my-blog---a-developers-tale-of-over-engineering-using-obsidian-hugo-and-github-pages/">Reddit Thread</a>.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
