<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/do-androids-dream-of-electric-sheep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1968 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/do-androids-dream-of-electric-sheep/</guid>
      <description>Not remembering much from my initial watch of Blade Runner, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect going into this one. I did really enjoy A Scanner Darkly by Dick, so I expected to like this one despite not knowing much. I was not disappointed, and after blowing through this in 2 days I can say I really enjoyed it.&#xA;The philosophical questions presented combined with the loose answers they provide were interesting and engaging enough for me to think about throughout the read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edgedancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/edgedancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/edgedancer/</guid>
      <description>Previous: Words of Radiance&#xA;Definitely a novella that took me too long to finish, and not really because I was enjoying it. More so because I didn&amp;rsquo;t love Lift as a character. I was actually going to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t hate their childish behavior, but typing that out I had a gut feeling I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself.&#xA;I really didn&amp;rsquo;t like how childish Lift was. Maybe that was her point, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp onto the story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oathbringer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/oathbringer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/oathbringer/</guid>
      <description>Holy Moly. What a ride. This book took FOREVER to finish. Exactly 3 months and a day to be exact. But it was so worth it.&#xA;A true continuation from Words of Radiance, this book follows the logical progression from where that book left off and really begins to open up the world. There are still lots of secrets left to unfold (Who is Wit? Who is the Cremling God that Lift meets in Edgedancer?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Road</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/the-road/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 14 2024&#xA;I finished The Road a few days ago and I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected fondly on the experience. Slow burn isn&amp;rsquo;t the word I&amp;rsquo;d use; perhaps a slow agonizing death. Because by the end, I was emotionally exhausted. It asks a lot of you. Sit through the gray, dim world that the story takes place in. Hope to some God the end is worth it. In my opinion, I think it was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words of Radiance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/words-of-radiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/entertainment/words-of-radiance/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 02 2024&#xA;I finished Words of Radiance two days ago, and it initially got a 4 out of 5. I loved the book. I really did, and was invested from start to finish.&#xA;It took me about 3 weeks (3 weeks and 3 days says Goodreads) and it really flew by. I enjoyed tackling such a huge tome of a novel.&#xA;The characters were awesome, even if I felt like the interlude characters could have been longer to make them a bit more memorable.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
