<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machinelearning on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/machinelearning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machinelearning on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/machinelearning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning - Chapter 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/deep-learning/deep-learning---chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/deep-learning/deep-learning---chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Linear Algebra This book covers all topics of linear algebra that are important to deep learning, not necessarily all topics within Linear Algebra. For a text more focused in linear algebra, see here.&#xA;Scalars, Vectors, Matrices, and Tensors Scalars Single numbers, usually denoted by a lowercase variable name, and introduced with some information on the number.&#xA;Ex.&#xA;Let $s \in R$ be the slope of the line for a real-valued scalar Let $n \in N$ be the number of units for a natural number scalar Vectors An ordered array of numbers, obtainable via the index position of the number in the array.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning - Preface</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/deep-learning/deep-learning---preface--chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/textbooks/deep-learning/deep-learning---preface--chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Preface MIT Press Online Edition Ian Goodfellow, Yoshua Bengio, and Aaron Courville Link to the book.&#xA;Chapter 1 Introduction This book is intended to prepare you for concepts and theory used in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence, more specifically deep learning, or the multi-layered stacked concepts that make up the intelligence of an AI model.&#xA;Like most textbooks, it goes into the why of AI, and what they do best; solving problems that humans are generally not good at.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Engineer Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/ai-engineer-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/ai-engineer-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>A resource by Code Basics&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ll see how this works. Starting in June of 2024, I plan to get myself prepared for a new career after another year of teaching. Pretty much; I want to find a job ideally that starts in the late summer of next year.&#xA;Week 0 is stupid lol.&#xA;Week 1 and 2 (6/2 - 6/17) I have a masters degree in this subject. I think I can handle a khan academy course and going through the entire Python documentation in two weeks.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
