<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entertainment on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entertainment on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Edgedancer</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/edgedancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/edgedancer/</guid>
      <description>Previous: Words of Radiance&#xA;Definitely a novella that took me too long to finish, and not really because I was enjoying it. More so because I didn&amp;rsquo;t love Lift as a character. I was actually going to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t hate their childish behavior, but typing that out I had a gut feeling I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself.&#xA;I really didn&amp;rsquo;t like how childish Lift was. Maybe that was her point, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp onto the story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oathbringer</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/oathbringer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/oathbringer/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Hero Academia</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/my-hero-academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/my-hero-academia/</guid>
      <description>by Kohei Horikoshi 2014 - 2024&#xA;Ah man. Ten years of My Hero. Crazy to think of where I was at 10 years ago, in High School myself, seeing these characters grow. Grow up into being one of the most meh pieces of work I&amp;rsquo;ve ever followed.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to even think of where My Hero fell off for me. I want to say it was watching alongside the anime and not really loving it, to around the time Deku started to gain more powers, nothing ever really felt memorable enough to make me want to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Road</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/the-road/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 14 2024&#xA;I finished The Road a few days ago and I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected fondly on the experience. Slow burn isn&amp;rsquo;t the word I&amp;rsquo;d use; perhaps a slow agonizing death. Because by the end, I was emotionally exhausted. It asks a lot of you. Sit through the gray, dim world that the story takes place in. Hope to some God the end is worth it. In my opinion, I think it was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words of Radiance</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/words-of-radiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/words-of-radiance/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 02 2024&#xA;I finished Words of Radiance two days ago, and it initially got a 4 out of 5. I loved the book. I really did, and was invested from start to finish.&#xA;It took me about 3 weeks (3 weeks and 3 days says Goodreads) and it really flew by. I enjoyed tackling such a huge tome of a novel.&#xA;The characters were awesome, even if I felt like the interlude characters could have been longer to make them a bit more memorable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Naruto</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/naruto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/naruto/</guid>
      <description>Modified: August 02 2024&#xA;by Masashi Kishimoto 1999 - 2014&#xA;I finished Naruto today. I really enjoyed reading it; I nearly flew through it in just over or under 3 months. I had a blast-Kishimoto&amp;rsquo;s art was really fun and emotive and kept me wanting to see just how each page would grow in more detail and impact. I think it delivered in that respect. The last 100 chapters had many great panels-none screenshot worthy in my opinion like the beginning/middle of the series but regardless a lot of fun.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Are Not Expected To Understand This</title>
      <link>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/you-are-not-expected-to-understand-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrpointing.com/notes/entertainment/you-are-not-expected-to-understand-this/</guid>
      <description>Modified: July 26 2024&#xA;26 short essays on the pieces/lines of code that shaped the modern understanding of computer science.&#xA;6/3/24&#xA;Halfway through, I think some of the stories are interesting. Some of the articles don&amp;rsquo;t go as deep as I think they could/should; some bring up gender/race for seemingly no reason&amp;hellip;others actually delve deeper into the politics of it encouragingly.&#xA;I started Topics I&amp;rsquo;m Interested In because of this book pretty much.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
