<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flask on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/flask/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flask on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/flask/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 30</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-30/</guid>
      <description>Goal Finish Portfolio prototype Accomplishments I was able to finish a basic prototype for the portfolio page but it kind of sucks.&#xA;I wanted to figure out an easy way to get the Instagram feed for the artist, but working with Meta&amp;rsquo;s API is almost as sucky as my portfolio page. So I honestly have my work cut out for me.&#xA;This has been a crazy 30 days. Technically more, but who&amp;rsquo;s counting?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 31 - Summary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/day-31---summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/day-31---summary/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I worked on this project for 30 days. The growth has been fantastic, and I should be proud of all that I was able to accomplish. If this is true, why do I feel a pit in my stomach when I think about this project? If I did such a good job, why do I feel like such crap?&#xA;To be honest, the more I worked on this the more I understood why it takes teams of people to produce applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 29</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-29/</guid>
      <description>Goal Complete the manual entry form Accomplishments FINALLY completed the manual entry form!! I&amp;rsquo;ve been building this out for a while and I was nervous to commit to it since there were a few more moving parts than just a regular request/booking. Happy to say it&amp;rsquo;s done and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty close to completion. The next and hopefully last big hurdle is the creation of the portfolio page, and ending with the testing of the hosting and such.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-28/</guid>
      <description>Goal Work on email formatting Finish search for bookings Look into pagination Accomplishments I finished the searching for the bookings table, and tweaked the functions around a bit. This time, instead of creating a second search function, I made a new parameter table that takes in the type of table you want to search from. This way, I can just create a second view for the page to view the bookings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-27/</guid>
      <description>Goal Accomplishments I got the search feature working! I honestly was pretty shocked at how easy it was to implement after I got past the initial hurdle of creating the correct SQL query.&#xA;Problems or Issues I had to change the SQL query that grabbed the search results to format it with the variables before trying to execute it. I think because I was using a question mark placeholder for both column and search term, it was messing up the column value with quotation marks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-26/</guid>
      <description>Goal Accomplishments I was able to get the progress from yesterday into a bit more of a tangible solution. Currently, in order to update the SQL table of when a booking has been confirmed, is when the embedded widget passes an event scheduled action, it will notify the window which will in turn send the scheduled events information to a Flask view. From there, I need to make another call using the events information unique identifier to retrieve the start time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-25/</guid>
      <description>Goal Accomplishments I worked for a bit yesterday and a lot today, so I&amp;rsquo;ll count them as one. I was able to implement some more font choices so we can narrow that down sooner rather than later, and was also able to work on the color scheme a bit.&#xA;Problems or Issues Today was a daunting experience. I was finally able to get the API connection with Calendly going, just to realize I&amp;rsquo;m getting into more unfamiliar territory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-24/</guid>
      <description>Goal Get current bookings page working Look into filtering requests/bookings Don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to refresh the page, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to constantly update as the user is typing. Results should only appear upon hitting enter. Accomplishments Current bookings was a lot easier now that I&amp;rsquo;m using a template for all my pages, and it was a breeze to create a new blueprint for the page since it&amp;rsquo;s even less code than the requests page, due to their not needing to handle any post requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-23/</guid>
      <description>Goal Coming back from a few days to think about a game plan for the finish line, I think I can get something out and working by the end of these 30 days. Maybe.&#xA;Finish applying base.html to all pages Make the admin index page for current requests page for current bookings page for manual application form Finish CSS for pages Accomplishments Got a ton done today, and worked for probably over 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-4/day-22/</guid>
      <description>Goal Start working on HTML/CSS changes Finish reformatting HTML with base.html Accomplishments Surprisingly, got a decent amount done in just under an hour. I was able to complete the base.html file, and worked out some of the kinks of the formatting. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look exactly like the Figma yet, but I want to make sure all of the HTML files have the base.html extension first.&#xA;Problems or Issues Next: Day 23</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-21/</guid>
      <description>Goal Get Calendly to prefill info for booking link Accomplishments I really thought todays goal was going to be harder, but it actually ended up being pretty easy. All I had to do was edit the URL and pass in some parameters. I thought maybe I&amp;rsquo;d have to set up a developer account and use JSON/JavaScript, but honestly it seems fine without it?&#xA;Problems or Issues Next: Day 22</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-20/</guid>
      <description>Goal Correctly sync the booking form to choose which type of session Caret drop down menu &amp;amp; link to appropriate function Small Tattoo Session Medium Tattoo Session Large Tattoo Session Small Tattoo Reschedule Medium Tattoo Reschedule Tattoo Touchup Accomplishments Got a ton done today; walked through the Figma with Big Boss and was able to get going on the layout. Promising results on that front shortly.&#xA;I was able to get the quick note I made down below finished pretty quick, and glad I did since that will help out immensely when I start building out the search/filter feature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-19/</guid>
      <description>Goal Finish the Figma for site Mess around on Calendly Accomplishments Finished the preliminary wireframe for the site, handed off to big boss So another rejection as far as my current layout for the site. I was able to get started and get an actual calendar embedded into the site which worked nicely. I now have a new slew of issues to worry about;&#xA;There are 3 types of bookings to account for Normal tattoo sessions, three types Small (&amp;gt;2hrs) Medium (2 - 5hrs) Large (5+hrs) Reschedules Small (2hrs) Medium (3hrs30) Touchups (1hr30) Change Admin&amp;rsquo;s booking page to choose which type of session Booking should generate and save a link to it in the SQLite database for use later Artist can send via dm with info already filled out Figure out how to give Calendly forms pre-saved information Problems or Issues Next: Day 20</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-18/</guid>
      <description>Goal Goals for today are quite simple; complete the look of the website on Figma, so the boss can come in and make design changes before I start committing any time towards building in HTML/CSS. I&amp;rsquo;m building out a basic skeleton for her to build off of, and I should be able to finish that today.&#xA;As far as the project is coming along, since we are moving away from using Full Calendar, I think we&amp;rsquo;re going to just integrate with Calendly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-17/</guid>
      <description>Goal First day back!&#xA;I was sick for maybe 2, 3 weeks? Probably the worst cold I&amp;rsquo;ve had in my life, and of course it happened in the midst of my 30 day challenge. I almost tried to work through it, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus at all and had to stop completely. Instead of calling it quits though, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start Day 17 over as a new day, and try and get back up on the saddle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-16/</guid>
      <description>Goal Honestly, I might be taking a small break today? I mostly wanted to get the ball rolling this week but after yesterday, I think I might have to settle for Calendly integration before trying to re-create their services. The Twilio account rejected my verification again, and after trying to build a working calendar system through JavaScript, I realized two things; I suck at JavaScript and don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, and Twilio has everything I&amp;rsquo;m looking for plus a little more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-3/day-15/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Set up text message for request Client Artist Integrate with Google Calendar For Today:&#xA;Change calendar to full month and change the formatting Had a talk with the boss, and she wants it to look a little bit different than the week-hour grid I had going on. Instead, I need each date to be clickable when available, and when clicked, needs to open up a little window in front with the available times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-14/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Set up text message for request Client Artist For Today:&#xA;Refactor for Yagmail instead of Gmail&amp;rsquo;s Oauth2 set up Refactor requests for asking for consent for text messages Create JSON file for artist schedule Integrate with Google Calendar? (maybe way down the line) Make a confirm booking button that checks to make sure there is no issue with timing Accomplishments Getting a lot done today; more so with understanding how the calendar features work for Fullcalendar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-13/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Accomplishments I looked more into Twilio and it seems like they have their own API that can be used to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s compliant with their rules. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try editing in a checkbox option that allows the user to check yes before submitting the application. If they don&amp;rsquo;t say yes, the database save will not include the phone number, save it as None, and text message reminders won&amp;rsquo;t be sent to them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-12/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Set up text message for request Client Artist For Today:&#xA;Booking Python file Figure out how Google Calendar works Accomplishments Had a good talk with the boss about the structuring of the site so far. I had misunderstood the need for a &amp;ldquo;fast form&amp;rdquo;, it really should just be a button that sends a booking form that she fills out the request details and customer information for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-11/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Set up text message for request Client Artist Accept Request &amp;amp; Booking Feature &amp;ldquo;Accept&amp;rdquo; button HTML site Booking HTML site Booking Python file (refactor requests to make recs_books?) Accomplishments I got a Twilio phone number waiting to be verified, added the booking form and all the logic to get there, as well as fixed a small issue where requests were stuck and would re-send after refreshing the page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-10/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Set up text message for request Client Artist For Today:&#xA;Accept Request &amp;amp; Booking Feature &amp;ldquo;Accept&amp;rdquo; button HTML site Booking HTML site Booking Python file (refactor requests to make recs_books?) Accomplishments Set up the text messaging API account.&#xA;Problems or Issues Next: Day 11</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-9/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Last Week:&#xA;Format the Email back to client For Today:&#xA;Set up email to Client w/ request form Set up email to Admin saying there&amp;rsquo;s a new request w/ client info Set up text messages for both Accomplishments I was able to get a decent chunk of things today for today. One thing that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to to stress is the prettification of all of my elements. I got the emails working, but they look like crap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-2/day-8/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Format the Email back to client Accomplishments Problems or Issues Tattooed today, so maybe today will be nice free day?&#xA;Next: Day 9</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-7/</guid>
      <description>Goal From Yesterday:&#xA;Format the Email back to client Accomplishments I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to work on this project much this weekend, and honestly I feel kind of okay about it? I am going to be putting off the AI roadmap on hold until this month is over to see if that helps with my workflow. This week I tried to do both and it left me really wanting to pick one over the other, so perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave the AI roadmap stuff on the back burner while I work hard on the next few days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-6/</guid>
      <description>Goal From yesterday:&#xA;Test email sending/receiving Format the Email back to client Accomplishments Today was a very busy work day, so I really didn&amp;rsquo;t get that far on anything. The biggest thing I did was I was able to locate the right documentation to help out with the next few steps. Otherwise, not a whole lot got done today.&#xA;Problems or Issues When running the Gmail quickstart code, I neglected to realize you would need to change the SCOPE list variable to allow more authorizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-5/</guid>
      <description>Goal From yesterday:&#xA;View Request Page (Admin page for Sarah) Work on getting pictures to display Test and integrate email to client &amp;amp; Sarah w/ request form Format the Email back to client Accomplishments Work Time: 1hr&#xA;So far so okay. I was able to finally get the images working, but I had to rely on ChatGPT for help since none of the videos I watched were able to really help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-4/</guid>
      <description>Goal From yesterday:&#xA;View Request Page (Admin page for Sarah) Work on the JOIN to bring client info along with each request Work on getting pictures to display Test and integrate email to client &amp;amp; Sarah w/ request form Format the Email back to client Accomplishments Work Time: 1hr 20&#xA;Not my best day, but to be expected. Today wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of my best days, so I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard on myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-3/</guid>
      <description>Goal From yesterday:&#xA;View Request Page (Admin page for Sarah) Python file (Flask View) HTML file (formatting) Work on the JOIN to bring client info along with each request For today:&#xA;Test and integrate email to client &amp;amp; Sarah w/ request form Format the Email back to client Accomplishments Work Time: 2 hours&#xA;While I didn&amp;rsquo;t get that much done as far as my lists are concerned, I was able to get a lot done today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-1/</guid>
      <description>Goal Write down a step-by-step initial guide to follow to help track/maintain progress Complete the initial booking form Set up the SQLite database/schema Accomplishments Work Time: 1hr 45&#xA;So today was the first day and I feel like I was able to make some pretty decent progress. I created a really simple step-by-step guide to keep me on track, and to make the scope less creepy. I also was able to get a working schema for my tables, and I currently have user for Sarah, client for all people who book, and a requests for initial requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/30-day-coding-challenge/week-1/day-2/</guid>
      <description>Goal From yesterday:&#xA;Complete the initial booking form For today:&#xA;Allow Images to be stored in SQLite database View Request Page (Admin page for Sarah) Accomplishments Work Time: 1hr 30&#xA;I got a lot done today, or at least it feels like it. First up, I messed around with the CSS Cursor gave me and tried to play with the setting up of the text entry fields for the requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flask&#39;s Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/flask-notes/flasks-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/flask-notes/flasks-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Link to tutorial.&#xA;I was really hesitant to start this note, since I basically ran through this tutorial once already to start and complete my final project, Lython. However, since I&amp;rsquo;m starting Sarah&amp;rsquo;s site, and I want to test out a bunch of features/really get to understand Flask, let&amp;rsquo;s go through it once more.&#xA;Last time, I did a combination of going through the tutorial, then making changes as I saw fit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flask&#39;s Templates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/flask-notes/flasks-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/flask-notes/flasks-templates/</guid>
      <description>Link to documentation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Flask Application via Apache</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/deploying-a-flask-application-via-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/deploying-a-flask-application-via-apache/</guid>
      <description>Modified: August 02 2024&#xA;Link to the project website.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lython</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/lython/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/lython/</guid>
      <description>Lython is my final project for my Masters program. I based it off an idea I had of giving my students a filtered AI, which branched off into editing ChatGPT with prompt filtering. Seeing that alone was particularly easy, I looked into implementing RAG, which works kind of.&#xA;Github&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d like to continue working on my project as an actual tool to use during class. I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to launch it to a production server, so my students can access it during class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flask&#39;s Quickstart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/flask-notes/flasks-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/python/flask-notes/flasks-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Link to documentation.&#xA;Flask is a framework to create applications via Python. It makes web based applications rather simple.&#xA;Starting from the here, the installation page.&#xA;Installation Python Version Python version should be up to date. Flask supports 3.8 and newer.&#xA;Dependencies The following are installed automatically when installing Flask:&#xA;Werkzeug uses WSGI, the standard Python interface between applications and servers. Jinja is a template language that renders the pages your application serves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing a RESTful API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/designing-a-restful-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/designing-a-restful-api/</guid>
      <description>Modified: August 02 2024&#xA;Watched this video to take some notes on what REST is.&#xA;API: Application Programming Interface, is how to computers can communicate with each other.&#xA;Client sends a Request to the server, server sends a response back to the client.&#xA;REST, or Representational State Transfer, is the most popular way to communicate with these web servers.&#xA;REST is actually a set of rules and standards. Any API that follows the REST rules is known as a RESTful API.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
