<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on Mr. Pointing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on Mr. Pointing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SQLBolt - Lesson 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-4/</guid>
      <description>Filtering and Sorting Results One way to ensure we don&amp;rsquo;t get duplicate rows, we could use the DISTINCT keyword;&#xA;SELECT DISTINCT column, another_column, ... FROM mytable WHERE condition(s); This however is pretty indiscriminate, and we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to specify duplicates with GROUP BY later.&#xA;Often in the real world, our data is not going to be ordered nice and neatly. Quite often, data is inserted without rhyme or reason, and purely based off when some events happened and collected rather than compared to the rest of the data in the data set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBolt - Lesson 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-6/</guid>
      <description>Multi-table Queries with JOINs Unlike the database we&amp;rsquo;ve been using for most of these lessons, real world data is usually divided into different tables, often through a process we call normalization. Normalization is the procedure used to break down large tables into smaller more organic tables. This reduces duplicate data, and allows for a more natural growth of data within respective tables.&#xA;Due to our data being broken up, our queries will in turn have to become more complex to grab information over multiple tables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBolt - Lesson 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-2--3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-2--3/</guid>
      <description>Specifying Data to Select (Constraints) When our table has only a few rows, a select * query isn&amp;rsquo;t so bad. However, if we have hundreds, sometimes thousands of rows of data, retrieving all of them at once becomes an issue.&#xA;That reason is why we have the ability to specify our results with conditional statements:&#xA;SELECT column, another_column, ... FROM mytable WHERE condition AND/OR another_condition AND/OR ...; We can collect more complex results from building more complex queries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBolt - Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---introduction/</guid>
      <description>Link to lessons.&#xA;Introduction to SQL What is SQL? Structured Query Language is a language used to create, maintain, and use relational databases. Thousands of applications from simple projects to Microsoft products use SQL through various formats and configurations.&#xA;Some use SQLite, MySQL, Postgres, Oracle, or Microsoft SQL, to name a few. Each use SQL as base, and include features that garner appeal from different developers.&#xA;Relational Databases A relational database is a collection of 2D tables that are linked through some key value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBolt - Lesson 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/computer-science/sql/sqlbolt/sqlbolt---lesson-1/</guid>
      <description>When we want to get information for a SQL table, we use the SELECT statement, or a query. Within a query is what data we want, where to get it from, and any additional formatting we want done before we get said data.&#xA;When selecting information from a table, we have to understand the make-up of a table. Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a reptiles table. There might be different types of reptiles (snakes, lizards, turtles, crocodiles) but each reptile has characteristics that make it unique.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
